Anteneh Beshah Wasie Cell: (+251) 0920 075718

Email: beshah.anteneh@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Driven IT expert with extensive experience in system administration, website development, system analysis and IT support, networking, and infrastructures to achieve organizational business goals. Excellent team player, result orientated, problem-solving capacity, good communicator, attention to details, reliable, confidentiality, trustworthiness & ethics, understanding of various programming languages, and have good coach and mentor skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

From 11 /2023 to present

Ethiopian Orthodox Church Mahibere Kidusan(EOTCMK) - Senior System Administrator

- Identifying system problem and providing solution, and supporting staffs in setting up desktop applications,
- Monitoring and installing office equipment, maintaining customer databases, efficiently handling incoming tickets, and maintaining comprehensive inventories of assets,
- Providing preventive assessment and maintenance of office IT machines which includes tracking, assessing, and conducting audits to maximize efficiency and data integrity.
- Creating and managing user accounts to access to computer systems, applications, and network resources in accordance with EOTCMK policies and procedures.
- Providing user orientation and training, designing and supporting corporate applications, updating the intranet site, and access rights for users.
- Monitoring users in adhering to EOTCMK policies.
- Installing and Configuring server applications, devices, and firewalls,
- Monitoring the performance of the server processes and upgrading the network infrastructure as needed, ensure the smooth deployment of new applications,
- Supervising operations team.

From 11/2022 to 09/2023

National Investment Group - Information and Technology lead

Responsibilities

Tolo Ride and Tolo Pay Projects

- Carried out the system testing as Agile System Tester
 - Troubleshot the system to get the final working application.
 - Developed test structures and assess the project output on its strength and weakness.
 - Tested the user acceptance (UAT)and provide the key elements for the development of the project.
 - Tested the reliability of the application developed using different testing tools.
 - Tested the application integration.
 - o Tools used for Testing: Test Rail, JIRA, Fitness, JMeter, LoudRunner, and Selenium tools.
- Worked as a frontend web developer
 - Created, implemented, and maintained user interfaces for the project's websites and web applications.
 - Worked in Collaborating with the designers and backend developers to ensure the project integration of design and functionality of the website.
 - o Wrote clean, scalable, and efficient code using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.
 - o Optimized the project websites and applications for maximum speed and scalability.
 - Troubleshot and debug frontend issues.
 - Conducted cross-browser and cross-device testing to ensure consistent user experience.

- Stayed up-to-date with the latest web development trends and best practices.
- o Tools used: Visual Studio and Node.

From 08/2020 to 12/2021

Kifiya Financial Technology PLC- Operation Associate and System Admin

Responsibilities

Che Delivery Project

- Installed, configured, and maintained the organization's computer and systems.
- Troubleshot and maintained the organization hardware, software, and other applications.
- Monitored system performance and identified potential problems.
- Controlled the implementation of security policies and procedures.
- Provided technical support for project staffs and others as required.
- Researched and recommend new technologies and solutions.
- Received and dispatched orders for products deliveries
- Maintained system logs, recorded call activities, and kept all data in the system.
- Managed the overall applications and smooth running of the website.
- Oversaw new product creation set-up and data management.
- Implemented Service Legal Agreement (SLA) and Standard Operating Procedures (SOP).
- Worked on Windows Server Unit to support the overall system support.

From 09/2015 to 06/2020

St. Mary University - System Analyst

Responsibilities

- Prepared Requirement analysis and designed document based on each department.
- Designed System Flow Diagram and implemented to each department.
- Provided training to instructors and relevant staffs for newly developed systems and its System Development Life Cycle (SDLC).
- Prepared Program Modules for the programmers and system developers.
- Advised any systems and security related issues when required.
- Configured the newly procured hardware as per the organization policy.
- Administered the Windows Server and the infrastructures.
- Worked closely with the Office Administration Team for office leases and extensions, utility requirements and payments, vehicle arrangements for monitoring visits of each site.
- Provided Technical Advice for Managements related to IT and System related issues.
- Tools used: Structured Analysis and Design Technique (SADT), Data Flow Diagrams (DFD), Decision Tables, Use Case, and prototypes.

From 11/2012 to 08/2015,

Metals & Engineering Corporation (METEC) - IT Support Officer

Responsibilities

- Provided preventive and fully or partially failed hardware and software maintenance.
- Prepared preventive training manuals and provided training.
- Troubleshoot and restored network connectivity and clean up malware and viruses from computers.
- Updated the system and software patches.
- Serviced Windows Servers, desktops, Personal Laptops, printers, and other peripheral equipment.
- Installed and configured network devices, such as routers, switches, and firewalls.
- Configured routing and switching, including static routes, OSPF, and BGP.
- Managed network security, including firewalls and virus detection.
- Troubleshoot network problems and identify and resolved network performance issues.
- Worked with other IT staffs to implement new network technologies, eg Drone Technology.
- Installed and integrating new server hardware and applications.

EDUCATION AND PROFFESSION STATUS

- MSC in Computer Science, HiLCoE School of Computer Science and Technology, 2020.
- BSC in Management Information System, Adama University, July 2010.

TRAININGS

- Full Stack Web (MERN) Development, Evangadi (Boot camp) Coding Academy, In progress
- IT Essentials, Cisco Networking Academy, March 2024
- HTML Course, WildLearner, February 2023
- Oracle Database Certificate, Addis Ababa University, June 2015.
- A+ Maintenance (Office Hardware Maintenance) Certificate, Award Computer Technology, June 2012

OTHER SKILLS

- Database Systems: MS-SQL and Oracle Database System, and MS Access
- Operating System: MS-Windows and Networking
- Programming Language: C++ and Java along with Data structure & Algorithm Analysis
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, BootStrap, Media Quiry, JQuery, and others
- Language: 1. Fluent in English and 2. Mother Tongue in Amharic

REFERENCES

- Dr. Sossina Mengistu, ICT Director, Ethiopian Orthodox Church Mahibere Kidusan(EOTCMK)
 ict@eotcmk.org 0911510245
- Getachew Kebede, Project Head, National Investment Group emailtogech@gmail.com Tel: 0944242323
- Tadesse Hailu, Project Manager for Che Delivery project, Kifiya Financial Technology, tadessehailu@gmail.com Tel: 0913847700
- Solomon Hunegnaw; Director of ICT Unit, St. Mary University, hunegnaws@gmail.com Tel: 0911687908